Ren d'Harnoncourt Papers
The Museum of Modern Art, Publisher
- Series IX: Art of Installation, 1930-1974
  - Subseries A: MoMA exhibitions at MoMA
    - The Sculpture of Picasso, 1967-68; Copy drawings of individual objects. (Folder IX.A.121)
    - The Sculpture of Picasso, 1967-68; Copies of labels and written information. (Folder IX.A.122)
    - The Sculpture of Picasso, 1967-68; Floor plans and distribution of objects. Oversize, see flat file at MoMAQNS. (Folder IX.A.123*)
  - Subseries B: MoMA exhibitions shown elsewhere
    - American Indian Art of the United States(Traveling Show), Early 1940s; Material on the traveling exhibition,American Indian Art of the United States. (Folder IX.B.1)
    - Paris -12 American Painters and Sculptors, 1953; Copies of installation photographs. (Folder IX.B.2)
    - Venice -Biennale(ICE-F-23-54), 1954; U.S. Representation at the XXVII Biennale di Venezia, 1954, at which RDH was the U.S. Commissioner. (Folder IX.B.3)
    - Barcelona -Modern Art in the United States(ICE-F-24-54), 1954; Exhibition at the Palacio de la Virreina and the Parque de la Ciuedala, Barcelona - III Bienal Hispanoamerica. (Folder IX.B.4)
    - Paris -Modern Art in the United States(ICE-F-24-54), 1955; Exhibition at the Muse national dart moderne, Paris. (Folder IX.B.5)
    - Venice -Biennale(ICE-F-67-61), 1962; Exhibition at the XXXI Biennale di Venezia. (Folder IX.B.6)
    - Paris -Modern Sculpture USA, 1965; Exhibition at the Muse Rodin, Paris. RDH original drawings of individual sculptures, and notes on pedestals. (Folder IX.B.7)
    - Paris -Modern Sculpture USA, 1965; Exhibition at the Muse Rodin, Paris. Photographs of installations, and copies of ground plans of the Muse Rodin. (Folder IX.B.8)
    - Paris -Modern Sculpture USA, 1965; Exhibition at the Muse Rodin, Paris. Transparencies of individual sculptures and installations. (Folder IX.B.9)
    - Paris -Modern Sculpture USA, 1965; Exhibition at the Muse Rodin, Paris. RDH original plans of the installation in the garden of the Muse Rodin. Oversize, see box 134. (Folder IX.B.10*)
    - Mexico City -School of Paris Schoenborn-Marx Collection(SP-ICE-35-65), 1966; Scrapbook containing newspaper clippings about the exhibition,La Escuela de Paris, at the Museo de Arte Moderna, Mexico City (7/2-8/16/66). RDH represented MoMA at the opening, and gave an address in Spanish. (Folder IX.B.11)
  - Subseries C: Exhibitions not related to MoMA
    - Mexican Arts- Catalogues, 1930-32; Catalogues of the exhibition,Mexican Arts, which was organized by RDH for the American Federation of Arts (1 in English, 1 in Spanish). The exhibition was circulated to 14 cities throughout the U.S. in 1930-32. (Folder IX.C.1)
    - Mexican Arts, 1930-32; Copy photographs of the exhibition,Mexican Arts, as it was installed at the Metropolitan Museum in New York, Oct./Nov. 1930. Copy of Carnegie Magazine with article, Exhibition of Mexican Arts, by RDH, published to coincide with the showing of the exhibition in Pittsburgh, 1/8-2/5/31. (Folder IX.C.2)
    - Mexican Arts, 1930-32; RDH original drawings of individual objects, installations, and floor plans. (Folder IX.C.3)
    - Mexican Arts, 1930-32; Copies of drawings of installations. (Folder IX.C.4)
    - Mexican Arts, 1930-32; Copies of photographs of installations. (Folder IX.C.5)
    - Mexican Arts, 1930-32; Photographs of Mexican paintings from the exhibition. (Folder IX.C.6)
    - Mexican Arts, 1930-32; Photographs of paintings and drawings from the exhibition. (Folder IX.C.7)
    - Mexican Arts, 1930-32; Floor plans of the exhibition. (Folder IX.C.8)
    - Indian Art in the United States and Alaska, 1939; Material about the Indian Arts and Crafts Board exhibition shown at the Golden Gate International Exposition, San Francisco, 1939. Brochure with map and plan of the exhibition. (Folder IX.C.9)
    - Indian Art in the United States and Alaska, 1939; Material about the Indian Arts and Crafts Board exhibition shown at the Golden Gate International Exposition, San Francisco, 1939. Microfilm record of the exhibition. (Folder IX.C.10)
    - Indian Art in the United States and Alaska, 1939; Material about the Indian Arts and Crafts Board exhibition shown at the Golden Gate International Exposition, San Francisco, 1939. Photographs printed from microfilm frames. (Folder IX.C.11)
    - Indian Art in the United States and Alaska, 1939; Material about the Indian Arts and Crafts Board exhibition shown at the Golden Gate International Exposition, San Francisco, 1939. Transparencies of posters for the exhibition. (Folder IX.C.12)
    - Indian Art in the United States and Alaska, 1939-41; Photograph of installation The Navaho Shepherds. It is not clear whether this photograph was taken at the 1939 exhibition, or at the MoMA exhibition in 1941. (Folder IX.C.13)
    - Arte Indigena de Norteamerica, 1944-45; Material on the exhibition of Indian art of North America shown in Mexico City in 1945. 1 TLS RDH - Miguel Covarrubias (11/9/44) enclosing a copy of the foreword to the exhibition catalogue. Copy of the catalogue. Original plans for the exhibition. Clippings about the exhibition in Mexico City -Arte Indigena de Norteamerica shown at the Museo Nacional de Antropologia. (Folder IX.C.14)
    - Kykuit, 1968; Installation of sculpture at Kykuit Gardens, Pocantico Hills (the Rockefeller Estate) by RDH, and his sketch for installation of Picassos Bathers, installed by NAR after RDHs death. (Folder IX.C.15)
  - Subseries D: Typescripts of the book on the art of installation; memos about the book, which was never published.
    - Mordechai Omer Book, 1968-74, Typescript. (Folder IX.D.1)
    - Mordechai Omer Book, 1968-74; Typescript. (Folder IX.D.2)
    - Mordechai Omer Book, 1968-74; Typescript. (Folder IX.D.3)
    - Mordechai Omer Book, 1968-74; Typescript. (Folder IX.D.4)
    - Mordechai Omer Book, 1968-74; Typescript. (Folder IX.D.5)
    - Mordechai Omer Book, 1968-74; Typescript. (Folder IX.D.6)
    - Mordechai Omer Book, 1968-74; Typescript. (Folder IX.D.7)
    - Mordechai Omer Book, 1968-74; Typescript. (Folder IX.D.8)
    - Mordechai Omer Book, 1968-74; Typescript. (Folder IX.D.9)
    - Mordechai Omer Book, 1968-74; Typescript. (Folder IX.D.10)
    - Mordechai Omer Book, 1968-74; Typescript. (Folder IX.D.11)
    - Mordechai Omer Book, 1968-74; Typescript. (Folder IX.D.12)
    - Mordechai Omer Book, 1968-74; Copy photographs of installations. (Folder IX.D.13)
    - Mordechai Omer Book, 1968-74; Copy photographs of installations. (Folder IX.D.14)
    - Mordechai Omer Book, 1968-74; Module for layout (and proposed dummy). (Folder IX.D.15)
    - Mordechai Omer Book, 1968-74; Omers original list of illustrations. (Folder IX.D.16)
    - Mordechai Omer Book, 1968-74; Captions for illustrations. (Folder IX.D.17)
    - Mordechai Omer Book, 1968-74; Draft typescript. (Folder IX.D.18)
    - Mordechai Omer Book, 1968-74; List of RDH exhibitions used by Omer. (Folder IX.D.19)
    - Mordechai Omer Book, 1968-74; Plans of MoMA exhibition spaces. (Folder IX.D.20)
    - Mordechai Omer Book, 1974; Copy of Omers work edited by Helen Franc, accompanied by a memo from Franc to Richard Oldenburg and Carl Morse (1/18/74) explaining what she has done. (Folder IX.D.21)
    - Mordechai Omer Book, 1974; Draft typescripts with Helen Franc memos. (Folder IX.D.22)
    - Mordechai Omer Book, 1968-74; File of memos about the proposed book - and more copies of drafts. (Folder IX.D.23)
    - Exhibition at Museum of Primitive Art, 1970; Galley copies of texts by Omer, edited by Ludwig Glaeser and Harriet Schoenholz, for the exhibition,Ren d'Harnoncourt: The Exhibitions of Primitive Art, held at the Museum of Primitive Art, 2/25 - 6/7/70. (Folder IX.D.24)
- Series X: Sarah d'Harnoncourt Donation, 1925-1970s
  Most of the material in this series was in the possession of Ren d'Harnoncourt's wife, Sarah, when he died. In addition to photographs, appointment books, passports and other travel documents, this series contains material from d'Harnoncourt's life in Mexico and the United States before he became officially associated with the Museum. Included are copies of childrens books he wrote and illustrated while he was in Mexico, and scripts of the national radio show he directed in the early 1930s. There are also some correspondence files documenting speeches and talks given by d'Harnoncourt, and honors received by him. In addition, the series contains articles and catalogue introductions written by d'Harnoncourt, and magazine and newspaper articles about him, some of these following his death. Also in the series are some strictly personal items, a few dating from d'Harnoncourt's early life in Austria.
  Two presentation boxes containing volumes with original drawings and dHoodles (doodles by d'Harnoncourt), which were given to the Museum by Mrs. Bliss Parkinson in July 1973, have also been included in this series.
  - Subseries A: Mexico, 1925-1932
    - Mexican Immigration Document, 1926; Document (in Spanish) recording personal information about RDH on the occasion of his entry into Mexico as an immigrant (1/6/26). It should be noted that this was not RDHs first entry into Mexico. That occurred in 1925. (Folder X.A.1)
    - Address and Appointment Notebook, 1929-30; Notebook for parts of 1929 and 1930 containing, in addition to addresses and appointments, information on RDHs collecting of objects to be used in the Mexican Arts exhibition. Contains loose notes by Sarah d'Harnoncourt explaining some of RDHs entries in the notebook, and providing additional information. (Folder X.A.2)
    - Address and Appointment Notebook, 1930; Notebook for part of 1930, apparently continuing where the 1929-1930 book left off. In addition to addresses and appointments, contains information on RDHs collecting of objects to be used in the Mexican Arts exhibition. Contains loose notes by Sarah d'Harnoncourt explaining some of RDHs entries in the notebook, and providing additional information. (Folder X.A.3)
    - Address and Appointment Notebook, Notebook containing addresses, appointments, and other information, n.d. (Folder X.A.4)
    - Mexican Sundays (Domingos Mexicanos), Late 1920s.; Mexican Sundays, a collection of reproductions of water color tableaus by Count Ren d'Harnoncourt, published by F.W. Davis, Mexico City, with a preface by Howard S. Phillips. Late 1920s. Note: This book, which was given to MoMA by Sarah d'Harnoncourt is rare and in fragile condition. (Folder X.A.5)
    - Photograph of Drawing by RDH, 1929; Photograph of drawing by RDH done in the style of Covarrubias. Given to MoMA by Sarah d'Harnoncourt. (Folder X.A.6)
    - Mexican Folkways Magazine 1928, Article by RDH in Mexican Folkways Magazine, Pancho el Juguetero (Pancho the Toy Maker) (In Spanish and English) (Folder X.A.7)
    - Note to RDH from Diego Rivera, 1929; Note in pencil to RDH from Diego Rivera (6/16/29). Envelope annotated by SDH. (Folder X.A.8)
    - Elizabeth Morrow Letter, Late 1920s-1930; Letter from Elizabeth Morrow (then wife of the U.S. ambassador to Mexico) addressed to Mr. Davis and Count d'Harnoncourt thanking them for a gourd they had sent her. n.d. (1927-30) (Folder X.A.9)
    - Mexican Folkways Magazine 1930, Article by RDH in Mexican Folkways Magazine, Las Artes Populares de Mxico - An Appreciation of the Origin and Development of the Popular Arts. (In Spanish and English). (Folder X.A.10)
    - The Painted Pig, 1930; Copy of The Painted Pig, book with text by Elizabeth Morrow, pictures by Ren d'Harnoncourt, published 1930 by Alfred A. Knopf, Inc. This copy of The Painted Pig was given to the Museum by Mrs. Irving Mathews in 1983. It has an inscription by RDH, and also a separate note of inscription by him. (Folder X.A.11.a)
    - The Painted Pig, 1930; Copy of The Painted Pig, book with text by Elizabeth Morrow, pictures by Ren d'Harnoncourt, published 1930 by Alfred A. Knopf, Inc. This copy of The Painted Pig was given to the Museum by Mr. David Chase, nephew of Mrs. Beulah Dimmick Chase, in July 2012. It has an inscription by RDH to Mrs. Chase, and also contains photograph of RDH in Mexico. (Folder X.A.11.b)
    - The Hole in the Wall, 1931; 1983; Copy of The Hole in the Wall by RDH, published 1931 by Alfred A. Knopf, Inc. This copy of The Hole in the Wall was given to the Museum by Mrs. Irving Mathews in 1983. It is inscribed by RDH. (Folder X.A.12)
    - The Hole in the Wall, 1931; 1982; Copy of The Hole in the Wall by RDH, published 1931 by Alfred A. Knopf, Inc. This copy of The Hole in the Wall was given to the Museum by Mrs. Henry I. Cobb, Jr. (Eliza Bliss Parkinson) in 1982. (Folder X.A.13)
    - The Hole in the Wall- Review, 1931; Review of The Hole in the Wall, Louisville, KY Courier Journal, 11/15/31. (Folder X.A.14)
    - Mexicana, 1931; Copy of Mexicana - A Book of Pictures by RDH, published 1931 by Alfred A. Knopf, Inc. (Folder X.A.15)
    - Scrapbook of Clippings on RDHs Childrens Books, 1930-32; Oversize scrapbook containing newspaper clippings about the childrens books by RDH - both those he wrote and illustrated, and those written by Elizabeth Morrow with illustrations by RDH. In fragile condition. Oversize, see box 135. (Folder X.A.16*)
    - Mexican Clippings, 1920s-1930; Folder containing miscellaneous newspaper clippings and other items from RDHs life in Mexico. (Folder X.A.17)
    - Sketch of Orozco, 1930s; Pencil caricature of the artist Jos Clemente Orozco done by RDH. This sketch was given to the Museum by Mr. David Chase, nephew of Mrs. Beulah Dimmick Chase, in July 2012. On the reverse, Mrs. Chase wrote "Ren d'Harnoncourt sketch of Oroxco [sic] given to me by the artist (BDC)." A further note by Mr. Chase states that the sketch was given to her by RDH after a major show of Mexican Art at the Met, where Mrs. Chase worked as editor of publications. (Folder X.A.18)
  - Subseries B: U.S. before MoMA, 1933-1944
    - Art in America Radio Programs, 1934-35; Typescripts of the radio programs directed by RDH in the 1930s. (Folder X.B.1)
    - Art in America Radio Programs, 1934-35; Typescripts of the radio programs directed by RDH in the 1930s. (Folder X.B.2)
    - Art in America Radio Programs, 1934-35; Typescripts of the radio programs directed by RDH in the 1930s. (Folder X.B.3)
    - Art in America Radio Programs, 1934-35; Typescripts of the radio programs directed by RDH in the 1930s. (Folder X.B.4)
    - Art in America Radio Programs, 1934-35; Typescripts of the radio programs directed by RDH in the 1930s. (Folder X.B.5)
    - Color Drawing by RDH, 1938; Color drawing by RDH entitled Model Room, dated 2/23/38. Notes on verso by Sarah d'Harnoncourt. Oversize, see box 136. (Folder X.B.6*)
    - Appointment Calendar, 1938; Appointment calendar for 1938. (Folder X.B.7)
    - Appointment Calendars, 1940; Appointment calendars for January, March, April, May, July 1940. (Folder X.B.8)
    - Appointment Calendars, 1940; Appointment calendars, August-December, 1940. (Folder X.B.9)
    - Indian Arts and Crafts Board Report, 1940; Indian Arts and Crafts Board report prepared by RDH for Inter-American Conference on Indian Life, Patzcuaro, Michoacan, Mexico (4/14-24/40). (Folder X.B.10)
    - Appointment Calendars, 1942; Appointment calendars, January-June, 1942. (Folder X.B.11)
    - Appointment Calendars, 1942; Appointment calendars, July-December, 1942. (Folder X.B.12)
  - Subseries C: Years at MoMA, 1944-1968
    - 1. Correspondence - speeches and honors
      - Inter-American Institute, 1944; Program of Inter-American Institute conference at which RDH was a speaker (10/14/44). (Folder X.C.1.1)
      - Inter-American Affairs, 1946; Copy letter from NAR to RDH enclosing a certificate officially acknowledging RDHs services to the Office of Inter-American Affairs, 1940-1944. (Folder X.C.1.2)
      - The Museum of Modern Art, 1946; 1 TLS John E. Abbott - RDH (11/22/46) telling RDH that he had been elected a Trustee of MoMA, to serve for a term to expire on June 30, 1949. (Folder X.C.1.3)
      - The Museum of Modern Art, 1947; 1 TLS NAR - RDH (7/15/47) telling RDH that he has been appointed Chairman of the Coordination Committee. (Folder X.C.1.4)
      - UNESCO, 1947; Copy of certificate from the Department of State (10/27/47) stating that RDH has been designated an Adviser on the U.S. Delegation to the 2nd session of the General Conference of UNESCO to be held at Mexico City, Nov. 6 - Dec. 3, 1947. (Folder X.C.1.5)
      - Cooper Union 90th Anniversary, 1949; Program for Convocation in honor of the 90th Anniversary of the inauguration of the Cooper Union, at which RDH read the Citation for the award of the Peter Cooper Medal for the Advancement of Art given to Frank Lloyd Wright. (11/2/49) (Folder X.C.1.6)
      - RDH Speeches, 1940s; Copies of speeches made by RDH in the 1940s. (Folder X.C.1.7)
      - Correspondence about Speeches and Lectures, 1947-51; General correspondence about RDH speeches and lectures, 1947-51. (Folder X.C.1.8)
      - Museum Collections Letter, 1947; Certificate (11/13/47) signed by William A.M. Burden, Chairman, Committee on the Museum Collections thanking RDH for his gift of the drawing Head of a Child by Everardo Ramirez, 11/13/47. (Folder X.C.1.9)
      - American Federation of Arts, 1948; Copy of speech given by RDH at the American Federation of Arts convention in Baltimore, (5/17/48,) and correspondence about it. (Folder X.C.1.10)
      - Association for Arts in Childhood, 1948-49; Short article, Art as a Universal Language, by RDH, published in the quarterly publication of the Association for Arts in Childhood. Correspondence about the article. (Folder X.C.1.11)
      - The Museum of Modern Art, 1949; Copy of letter AHB - William M. Milliken, director, Cleveland Museum of Art (2/24/49), nominating RDH to represent MoMA in the Association of Art Museum Directors. (Folder X.C.1.12)
      - Carleton College, 1949; Correspondence and drafts of speech made by RDH at Dedication of Art Building, Carleton College, Northfield, Minnesota, (10/14/49.) (Folder X.C.1.13)
      - UNESCO, 1950; Letter from RDH to Peter Bellew, Editor, UNESCO publication (12/28/50), enclosing article, Art as Means of Communication: A Study of Indian Arts of the United States, together with contract to write the article. (Folder X.C.1.14)
      - Brearley School, 1951; Correspondence and copy of remarks made at a Parents Panel held at the Brearley School. (Jan. / Feb.1951) (Folder X.C.1.15)
      - Fordham University, 1951; Correspondence about a talk to be given at Fordham University by RDH on March 3, 1951. (Folder X.C.1.16)
      - Corning Conference, 1951; Correspondence and other material on the Corning Conference, Living in Industrial Civilization, (sponsored by the Corning Glass Works) held May 17-19, 1951 in Corning, New York. RDH was a participant. (Folder X.C.1.17)
      - French Legion of Honor, 1952; Copy correspondence between RDH, the French Ambassador and other French officials about RDH being named a Chevalier of the Legion of Honor, March and April, 1952. (Folder X.C.1.18)
      - University of Colorado Boulder, 1952-53; Correspondence and other material on RDHs trip to the University of Colorado, Boulder, where he gave three lectures on modern art Feb. 4, 5, and 6, 1953. (Folder X.C.1.19)
      - American Anthropological Association, 1953-54; Brief correspondence between RDH and Malcolm Collier, Assistant Editor of the American Anthropologist, about the possibility of RDH writing an article related to the Andes exhibition. (Folder X.C.1.20)
      - Dartmouth College, 1955; Commencement program, June 12, 1955, at which RDH was given the honorary degree, Doctor of Humane Letters by Dartmouth College. (Folder X.C.1.21)
      - Columbia University, 1958; Commencement program, correspondence and other material on RDHs receiving the honorary degree, Doctor of Humane Letters, from Columbia University, June 3, 1958. (Folder X.C.1.22)
      - German Officers Cross, 1958; Correspondence about the bestowal on RDH of The Officers Cross of the Order of Merit of the Federal Republic of Germany. The honor was given to RDH and also to William Burden, president of MoMAs Board of Trustees, for their part in organizing the exhibition, German Art of the Twentieth Century, Oct. 2-Dec. 1957. (Folder X.C.1.23)
      - Letter from NAR to RDH, 1960; 1 TLS NAR - RDH (2/25/60) in which he speaks of their friendship over the years. (Folder X.C.1.24)
      - Letter to RDH from President Kennedy, 1961; 1 TLS President Kennedy - RDH (9/8/61) saying that he and Mrs. Kennedy had enjoyed going through the albums of letters from artists and writers who were invited to the Inauguration ceremonies, and that he was hopeful that this collaboration between government and the arts would continue and prosper. (Folder X.C.1.25)
      - Article on Nave Painting, 1961; Article and drafts of article on nave painting by RDH, with a little correspondence. Nearly all in German. (Folder X.C.1.26)
      - American Federation of Arts, 1963; Copy of address given by RDH at the 1963 convention of the American Federation of Arts, Fort Worth, Texas (5/23/63). (Folder X.C.1.27)
      - University of New Mexico Albuquerque, 1964; Program for Dedication of the Fine Arts Center at the University of New Mexico, Albuquerque, (10/20/64) at which RDH received the honorary degree, Doctor of Fine Arts, together with the original degree certificate. (Folder X.C.1.28)
      - University of New Mexico Albuquerque, 1964; Correspondence about the dedication of the Fine Arts Center. (Folder X.C.1.29)
      - Wisdom Encyclopedia, 1965-66; Wisdom Award of Honor presented to RDH by Wisdom Magazine and The Wisdom Society, and correspondence about the award, 1965-66. (Folder X.C.1.30)
      - Citizenship-Constitution Day, 1966; Photographs and captions listing those present at the 1966 Citizenship-Constitution Day, an annual observance at Federal Hall National Memorial, New York. RDH was one of a group of outstanding New Yorkers who had achieved success since their arrival as immigrants, and who each received a Citizenship Achievement Award scroll issued by the City of New York, and signed by Mayor John V. Lindsay. (Folder X.C.1.31)
      - Louis Kahn Dinner, 1966; Draft of speech by RDH at opening dinner for exhibition,Louis I. Kahn, (4/26 - 5/30/66). (Folder X.C.1.32)
      - Letter to RDH from Mrs. Lyndon B. Johnson, 1967; 1 TLS Lady Bird Johnson - RDH (11/7/67) thanking RDH for sending her the catalogue of the Picasso exhibition, and saying that she and the President were delighted that RDH and his wife could be with them the other evening. (Folder X.C.1.33)
      - Lillie P. Bliss International Study Center, 1968; Program for the Dedication of the Lillie P. Bliss International Study Center of The Museum of Modern Art, May 27, 1968. Press releases. (Folder X.C.1.34)
    - 2. Correspondence - travel
      - Travel, 1940s-1950; Miscellaneous travel items - itinerary, tickets - late 1940s-1950. (Folder X.C.2.1)
      - Travel, 1948-66; Passports issued in the years 1948, 1953, 1957, 1961, 1966. (Folder X.C.2.2)
      - Travel, 1950s-1960s; International Certificates of Vaccination. (Folder X.C.2.3)
      - Travel, 1953; Miscellaneous travel items - itineraries, tickets, bills, memos. (Folder X.C.2.4)
      - Travel, 1954-55; Miscellaneous travel items - tickets, hotel bills. (Folder X.C.2.5)
      - Travel, 1954-55; Miscellaneous travel items - itineraries, memos to RDH while he was away from his secretary, Joyce Miller. Some postcards to Joyce Miller from Sarah d'Harnoncourt, and from staff members. (Folder X.C.2.6)
      - Travel, 1950s; Miscellaneous travel items - bills, expense reports. (Folder X.C.2.7)
      - Travel, 1956-57; Miscellaneous travel items - bills, tickets. Also some Requests for Publications memos related to travel books. (Folder X.C.2.8)